A Guide to the Records of the Virginia State Historical Records Advisory Board, 1969-1996
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the Virginia State Historical Records Advisory Board, 1969-1996
The Library of Virginia
42662, 31782, 32118, 32449, 32450, 32708, 34150, 35135
5.75 cu. ft. (12 boxes)
Office of the State Archivist
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred by the Office of the State Archivist.
Biographical Information
Authorized by federal law in the 1970s, the State Historical Records Advisory Board serves as the central advisory body for historical records planning and related projects developed and carried out by the State. Board members are appointed by the Governor and serve a three year term. The Board may publish and sponsor surveys of conditions and needs of historical records in the State; review records and proposals by institutions in the State; and make recommendations to the National Historical Publications and Records Commission.
Scope and Content
These collections contain correspondence, grant applications and evaluations, surveys, reports, meeting minutes, and agendas.
Accession 42664 (1969-1976) consists of correspondence between the LVA, NHPRC, and board members.
Accession 31782 (1976-1982) consists of grant files which were submitted to or reviewed by SHRAB from institutions across the state including the University of Virginia, the Colonial Williamsburg Foundation, Virginia Military Institute, and others.
Accession 35135 (1976-1996) predominantly spans the 1980s through the 1990s, and includes correspondence, publications, as well as grant applications and evaluations.
Accession 32450 (1982-1984) documents the Needs Assessment survey and subsequent report. The survey was sent out to institutions across the state including local and state agencies, circuit courts, and institutional archives. The report was released in 1983.
Accession 32118 (1983) contains more grant applications and related records, from the Blue Ridge Heritage Archives, George Mason University, and Mary Baldwin College.
Accession 34105 (1983-1986) consists of general correspondence and documents from conferences attended.
Accession 32449 (1983-1986) consists of grant applications, evaluations, and related records from institutions such as the Roanoke Transportation Museum and Washington and Lee University among others.
Accession 32708 (1985-1988) consists of general correspondence as well as grant applications and evaluations, specifically for the MacArthur Memorial, the National Recreation and Parks Association, and the Virginia Historical Society.
Arrangement
These collections are arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- General Correspondence and Guidelines, Acc. 42664, 1969-1976. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1969-1975. (Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1976. (Folder 2)
  - Guidelines, 1976. (Folder 3)
- Project Files, Acc. 31782, 1976-1982. (Box 2)
  - University of Virginia, 1976-1978. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Hollins College, 1977-1981. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Virginia Military Institute, 1978-1979. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Colonial Williamsburg Foundation, 19779-1981. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Franklin County, 1980. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Hadley Library, 1980. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Jones Memorial Library, 1980. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Spotsylvania County, 1980. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Fairfax County, 1980-1982. (Box 1, Folder 9, Box 2, Folder 1-4)
  - Newport News Public Library, 1980-1982. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - George Mason University, 1982. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- SHRAB Correspondence and Files, Acc. 35135, 1976-1996. (Box 1-2)
  - Board Appointments, 1984-1992. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Conflict of Interest Policy. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Long Range Planning, 1989. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Financials, 1992. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Administrative Support Grant, 1993-1994. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Strategic Planning Grant and Retreat, 1993. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Proposed Legislation and Correspondence, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - SHRAB Workshop Participant List. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - SHRAB Workshop Materials. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1988. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Memorandum, 1989. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1989. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Memorandum, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1991. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1992. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Minutes, 1982. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Minutes, 1983. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Minutes, 1984. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Minutes, 1986. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Minutes, 1987. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Wintergreen, 1988 Nov. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Richmond, 1989 Jan 27. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Richmond, 1989 Mar 15. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Roanoke, 1989 Mar 15. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Williamsburg, 1989 Sept 11. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Alexandria, 1989 Nov 14. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Richmond, 1989 Dec 1. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Richmond, 1990 Apr 12. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Fredericksburg, 1990 May 21. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Fredericksburg, 1990 July 13. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Richmond, 1990 Sept 14. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Statewide Conference, 1990 Oct 1-1991 Feb 14. (Box 1, Folder 22-23)
  - Richmond, 1991 Mar 14. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - NAGARA, 1991 July. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Richmond, 1992 Mar 12. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Richmond, 1992 Nov 6. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Strategic Planning Workshop, 1993 Jan. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Virginia Union University, 1993 Dec 9. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Williamsburg, 1994 Mar 15. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Richmond, 1994 Apr 26. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Clifton Forge, 1994 Nov 29. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Conservation Grant Cycles. (Box 1, Folder 33-34)
  - Conservation Grant: Non Receipients, 1989. (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Conservation Expenditures, 1985-1987. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Conservation Report, 1988. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Committee Thank You Letters, 1989. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Conservation Grant Survey, 1989-1990. (Box 1, Folder 39-41)
  - Grant Applications and Evaluations, 1989-1993. (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Shenandoah County Recommendation, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Arlington Public Library Application and Evaluation, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1982. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1982. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - NHPRC, 1979-1987. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Statement of Priorities and Approaches for Historical Programs, 1980. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Grant Application Guidelines, 1980-1984. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Guidelines for Evaluating Grants, 1986. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Plan for Improving Grant Proposal Process, 1987. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Guidelines for Re-Grant Process, 1987. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - University of Virginia, 1980 May 23. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Virginia Union University, 1993 Dec 9. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Richmond, 1994 Nov 10. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Re-Grant Application, 1985-1987. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Conservation Survey, 1989. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Project Hope, 1989-1991. (Box 2, Folder 14-16)
  - Shenandoah County, 1989-1991. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Grant Applications and Evaluations, 1989-1991. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Grant Applications and Evaluations, 1991-1992. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Virginia Historical Society, 1991-1994. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Marymount University, 1992. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University, 1993-1995. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Valentine Museum, 1994. (Box 2, Folder 23-24)
  - Virginia Home for Boys, 1994-1995. (Box 2, Folder 25-26)
- Needs Assessment Reports, Acc. 32450, 1982-1984. (Box 1-3)
  - Cover Letter for Questionnaire, 1982. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Manucript Log Sheets, 1982. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Clerks of Circuit Courts, 1982. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Municipal Clerks and Local Administrators and Managers, 1982. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - State Agencies, 1982. (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - Institutional Archives, 1982. (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Cover Letter for QuestionnaireNeeds Assessment Report, 1983. (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
  - Needs Assessment Report: State, Circuit Court 1983. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Needs Assessment Report: Local Government, Historical Repositories, 1983. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Institutional Archives, 1984. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Map of Survey Responses, 1982-1983. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Project Files, Acc. 32118, 1983. (Box 1)
  - Blue Ridge Heritage Archives, Ferrum College, 1983. (Folder 1)
  - George Mason University, 1983. (Folder 2-3)
  - Mary Baldwin College, 1983. (Folder 4)
- General Correspondence, Acc. 34105, 1983-1986. (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1983. (Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence and Conference Records, 1984-1986. (Folder 2)
- Project Files, Acc. 32449, 1983-1986. (Box 1)
  - Fairfax County Circuit Court, 1983-1984. (Folder 1)
  - American Alliance for Health, Physical Education, Recreation, and Dance, 1984. (Folder 2)
  - Robert R. Moton Institute, 1984. (Folder 3)
  - Washington and Lee University, 1984-1985. (Folder 4)
  - Roanoke Transportation Museum, 19841985-1986. (Folder 5-6)
  - American Alliance for Health, Physical Education, Recreation, and Dance, 1986. (Folder 7)
  - George Mason University, 1986. (Folder 8)
- Project Files, Acc. 32708, 1985-1988. (Box 1)
  - MacArthur Memorial, 1985-1988. (Folder 1-2)
  - National Recreation and Parks Association, 1985-1987. (Folder 3-4)
  - Virginia Historical Society, 1987. (Folder 5)